Michael Z. Lai

Michaelzlai@gmail.com · 336.575.2450 · michaelzlai.com · • michaelzlai

Dedicated weightlifter, perpetual "googler", and team player. I offer energy, enthusiasm, and perspective when engaging different environments to enrich my experience as well as those around me.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

General Assembly — Washington, DC

Web Development Immersive Student

SEPTEMBER 2016 - PRESENT

- · Built fluency in full-stack web development by completing an intensive three-month program focused on delivering best practices in object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and test-driven development.
- Developed four capstone projects over the 12 week program, including an interactive photo map app built in Angular.js with a Node backend, a restaurant generator utilizing mapbox and yelp APIs built in Angular.js with a Ruby on Rails backend, a fitness tracker app built with Ruby on Rails and a hangman game constructed in JavaScript.

IBM — Washington, DC

Senior Consultant

MARCH 2013 - SEPTEMBER 2016

- · Served as the API Lead managing development and functional tasks regarding GSA's SAM API. Since the API's inception on December 2014, 7 iterative versions have been deployed and maintained.
- · Assisted a tiger team assessing GSA's Sam.gov accessibility compliance with Section 508 of the Rehabilitation Act, primarily serving as the 508 compliance SME focused on users who rely on assistive technology.
- · As the Testing Team Database SME, utilized SQLdeveloper to create dummy data when implementing enhancements, resolving defects, and correcting maintenance issues within Agile and Waterfall deployments.

Credit Suisse — Raleigh, NC

IT Production Services Intern

MAY 2012 - AUGUST 2012

· Assisted a Lean Six Sigma Greenbelt project that improved data quality within the ticket monitoring system. Identified an opportunity to improve correlation and mapping of data sets and developed a VBA macro to expedite the process. Benefits include a decreased error rate and a savings of 15 minutes per instance.

B/E Aerospace — Winston-Salem, NC

Product Support Intern

MAY 2010 - JULY 2010

· Performed static and dynamic testing of seat products to verify maximum failure stress levels and confirmed measurements of products on Uni-Graphics. This provided confidence about the dimensions and allowances of the product before production.

SKILLS

Front End Development Javascript/jQuery, Angular.js, React.js, Vue.js, Canvas, D3.js, API/AJAX, HTML5/CSS3

Back End Development Rails, Ruby, Sinatra, Express.js, Node.js

Databases PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB

PROJECTS

SnapMap

Front End: Angular.js Back End: Node.js Database: MongoDB

Feed Me

Front End: Angular.js Back End: Ruby on Rails Database: PostgreSQL

WODLeader

Front End: Ruby on Rails Back End: Ruby on Rails Database: PostgreSQL

2 Person Hangman Front End: Javascript

EDUCATION

General Assembly

DECEMBER 2016 Web Development Immersive Student

North Carolina State University

DECEMBER 2012

B.S. of Industrial Engineering – minor in Statistics

AWARDS/CERTIFICATIONS

Geocent Hackathon SEPTEMBER 2016 1st Place

Lean Six Sigma Yellowbelt